Pranav Ahuja

I am a self-motivated, positive attitude person with a curiosity to learn things. My inspiration came from a world that has been integrated together and everything I do, learn and experience is the step towards inculcating the same. Being an Electronics enthusiast, I have worked in the field of IOT (Internet of Things) and Embedded Systems. I have experience working on STM32, AVR, Node MCU, ESP32, Arduino. I have experience in programming languages like C, Embedded C, C++, Python, Java, HTML, CSS.

CONTACT

+91 9650691311

pranav.ahuja3@gmail.com

https://pranav-ahuja.github.io/pranavahuja/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/pranav-ahuja-17094a14a/

EXPERIENCE

System Engineer

Infosys · November 2020 - Present

- SAP ATTP
 - o Regulatory reporting for Indonesia, Europe, China.
 - o Master data creation and processing.
 - Serialization and serial number management.
- Trainings
 - JAVA
 - Data Structure
 - o SQL
 - o SAP MM
 - SAP ATTP

Intern

Defense Research and Organization · June 2019 - July 2019

- Research in Missile Guidance Systems
 - Classification of Missiles and their working.
 - o Classification of Missile Guidance Systems.
 - Aerodynamics

PROJECTS

Unmanned Aerial Vehicle

January, 2022 - Present

- Build an UAV using Arduino Flight Controller.
- Components includes, Accelerometer sensor, ESC, Brushless Motors, nRF24L01 communication modules, Joystick, Arduino Uno, Arduino Nano.

Bicycle Theft Alarm

October, 2021 - November, 2021

- Build an alarm system triggered bicycle anti theft device.
- Works using GSM module.
- Sense the motion of the bicycle using motion sensor.
- It will place a call to your mobile device.

Posture Monitoring Device

June, 2019 - January, 2020

- Build a posture monitoring device, based on ESP32 micro controller.
- Correct the posture by producing vibration signals, if wrong posture is detected.
- Send the data to mobile phone using Bluetooth.



SKILLS

Embedded C C++ Python
HTML CSS Leadership IOT
Circuit Design PCB Design
Thingworx Arduino STM32
AVR ESP32 Node MCU

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology Major: Electronics and Telecommunication 2016 - 2020 | 9.32 CGPA

COURSES

IOT Devices University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign

Microcontroller Embedded C Programming Udemy

CERTIFICATIONS

Infosys IOT Professional Certificate

Infosys . April-2022